Register of the Anatole S. Loukashkin Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Anatole S. Loukashkin papers
1901-1989
2001C61
Hoover Institution Archives
33 microfilm reels (5 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, financial and legal records, minutes, printed matter, and photographs, relating to the Russian Center of San Francisco, the San Francisco newspaper Russkaia zhizn', and various aspects of Russian history and Russian émigré affairs.
Loukashkin, Anatole S., 1902-1988
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biography
A. S. Loukashkin was born in Liaoian, China, on 3 May 1902 (N.S.): his father was an employee of the Chinese Eastern Railway. Receiving his schooling in Chita, he returned to China following the Revolution, where he graduated from the Harbin Institute of Oriental and Commercial Studies. He worked as a curator of the Museum of the Society for the Study of Manchuria (Obshchestvo izucheniia Man'chzhurskogo kraia) in the 1930's. Upon arrival in the United States in 1941, he transferred his skills to the California Academy of Sciences, where he became an authority on the Pacific sardine (Sardinops Caerulea).
More significant was his participation in various Russian organizations: he was executive director of the Federatsiia russkikh blagotvoritel'nykh organizatsii (involved in helping Russian displaced persons relocate to the United States following the Second World War), served on the boards of the Russian Center of San Francisco and Russian Life Corporation, which published the newspaper Russkaia zhizn'. For over a decade (1954-1965) he served as director of the Museum of Russian Culture, in particular acquiring for it a voluminous amount of material about Russians in China. Loukaskin died in San Francisco on 6 October 1988.
Chronology
1902 May 3 Born, Russia
1932 Appointed director, Muzei Obshchestva izucheniia Man'chzhurskogo kraia, Harbin, China
1941 Arrived, United States
1988 October 6 Died, San Francisco, California
Scope and Content Note
A. S. Loukashkin was a biologist and the director of the Muzei Obshchestva izucheniia Man'chzhurskogo kraia in Harbin, China, and the Museum of Russian Culture in San Francisco, California. He also served on the boards of the Russian Center and Russian Life Corporation, which published the newspaper Russkaia zhizn' (San Francisco, California); two series so named reflect his activities in these organizations. The collection contains a small number of Loukashkin's scientific writings and a large quantity of collected materials on a variety of subjects, primarily Russians in China, the United States, and other countries. The PRINTED MATTER series contains rare issues of Russian émigré periodicals, especially those published in China.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Russian Center (San Francisco, Calif.); Russia--History.; Russia.; Russians--United States.; United States.
- Correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Cards and letters
- Speeches and Writings, 1934-1985 and undated (Box 1)
  Articles, poetry and translations, arranged chronologically by title
- Russian Center of San Francisco File, 1930-1975 (Box 1-8)
  Charter, clippings, correspondence, financial records, founding documents, legal records, list of members, minutes of meetings, printed matter, and speeches, relating to the activities and functioning of the Russian Center of San Francisco, Inc., and its predecessors - the Russian Club, Russkoe Natsional'noe Ob"edinenie, and others, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Russkaia Zhizn' File, 1942-1989 (Box 8-10)
  Articles, charter, clippings, correspondence, court records, financial records, minutes of meetings, poster, program, miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form, relating to the operations of Russkaia zhizn', published in San Francisco, California
- Subject File, 1905-1983 (Box 10-23)
  Clippings, correspondence, writings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
- Printed Matter, 1901-1978 (Box 23-30)
  Booklets, clippings, journals, and newspapers, arranged alphabetically by physical form, and therein by author or title
- Oversize File, 1908-1974 (Box 31-32)
  Newspapers and scrapbooks, arranged alphabetically by physical form, and therein by title (for newspapers) and subject (for scrapbooks)
- Photographs, 1903-1972 and undated (Box 33-34)
  Two albums depicting the construction of the Khukhai Railway, one album depicting events and people associated with the newspaper Russkaia zhizn', 69 loose prints and four negatives, depicting subjects such as the Russian Center of San Francisco, Anna Marly, the 22 nd Invalids' Ball, President Dwight D. Eisenhower with A. S. Loukashkin
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1934-1985 and undated
  General note
  See also RUSSIAN CENTER OF SAN FRANCISCO FILE and RUSSKAIA ZHIZN' FILE for speeches and reports made to the boards of directors and general meetings of members of these organizations, and SUBJECT FILE for Loukashkin's speeches and writings (primarily anniversary notes, polemics, letters to the editor, and similar matter for newspapers) relating to Boy scouts and other subjects of interest to Loukashkin
  - General
    - Poetry, 1984-1985 (Folder 1: 2)
      Typescript
    - Translations of Russian-language articles by others on sardines, 1952-1954 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Introduction to N. A. Baikov and I. V. Kozlov, "Ekskursii v dolinu reki Mudan'tszian," (Folder 1: 4)
    Printed copy
  - Introduction to N. N. Gomboev, Man'chzhuria glazami okhotnika, n.d. (Folder 1: 5)
  - "Novye ornitologicheskie nakhodki i nekotorye nabliudeniia nad ptitsami Severnoi Man'chzhurii," Vestnik Man'chzhurii, 1934 (Folder 1: 6)
  - "The Tarbagan or the Transbaikalian Marmot and Its Economic Value," Comptes rendus du XIIe Congrès international de zoologie, (offprint dated )., 1935 1937 (Folder 1: 7)
  - "The Tarbagan or the Transbaikalian Marmot as a Carrier of Plague," Comptes rendus du XIIe Congrès international de zoologie, (offprint dated )., 1935 1937 (Folder 1: 8)
  - "Mammals, Collected by the Dalai-Khingan Zoological Expedition of Manchuria Research Institute at Harbin, in 1935," Bulletin of the Institute of Scientific Research, Manchoukuo, 1937 June (Folder 1: 9)
  - "Mammals found on the Territory of Greater Harbin," Report of the Institute of Scientific Research, Manchoukuo, 1938 August (Folder 1: 10)
  - "On the Avifauna of North Manchuria," Report of the Institute of Scientific Research, Manchoukuo, 1939 March (Folder 1: 11)
  - "Fragments on the Question of Natural Food of Some North Manchurian Birds," Report of the Institute for Horse-Diseases, 1940 (Folder 1: 12)
  - "The General Report and Diary of the Assistant to the Chief of the Expedition of the Scientific Research Institute in the Region of Wutalienchieh in the Summer of 1937," Bulletin of the Institute of Scientific Research, Manchoukuo, 1940 June (Folder 1: 13)
  - "On the Pikas of North Manchuria," Journal of Mammalogy, 1940 November 14 (Folder 1: 14)
  - "On the Hares of Northern Manchuria," Journal of Mammalogy, 1943 February (Folder 1: 15)
  - "A Preliminary Report on the Behavior of the Pacific Sardine (Sardinops Caerulea) in an Electrical Field, " Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences, 1952 April 16 (Folder 1: 16)
  - "Further Studies of the Behavior of the Pacific Sardine (Sardinops Caerulea) in an Electrical Field," Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences, 1954 July 9 (Folder 1: 17)
  - "On the Pacific Sardine (Sardinops Caerulea Girard) in Aquaria: Transportation, Handling, Maintenance, and Survival," Proceedings of the California Academy of Sciences, 1955 June 30 (Folder 1: 18)
  - "Pusanskii gubernator: Svetloi pamiati Dimitriia Gerasimovicha Romanova,"., 1967 March 1 (Folder 1: 19)
  - "Kazach'ia pechat' v Man'chzhurii," Novyi zhurnal, 1973 (Folder 1: 20)
  - "K bibliografii dal'nevostochnoi pressy: Studencheskaia pressa Kharbina," Novyi zhurnal, 1974 (Folder 1: 21)
  - "Mongol'skie elementy v faune mlekopitaiushchikh v Severnoi Man'chzhurii," Zoologicheskii zhurnal, 1975 (Folder 1: 22)
  - "Vladimir Nikolaevich Zhernakov,"., 1977 August 19 (Folder 1: 23)
- RUSSIAN CENTER OF SAN FRANCISCO FILE, 1930-1975
  - General (Folder 1: 24)
  - Charter, n.d. (Folder 1: 25)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1973 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Financial records, 1939-1968
    - General, 1951 (Folder 2: 2)
      Documents relating to the theft of funds
    - Mortgage records (Folder 2: 3)
    - Reports
      - 1939-1950 (Folder 2: 4)
      - 1951-1953 (Folder 2: 5)
      - 1954-1968 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Founding documents, 1939 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Legal records, 1952 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Lists (Box 3)
    - Members of the Russian Center, 1969 (Folder 3: 1)
    - Members of the Russian Center Executive Committee, 1946-1969 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Organizations-members of the Russian Center, 1952 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Minutes of meetings.
    Includes attachments
    - 1941-1949 (Folder 3: 4)
    - 1950 (Folder 3: 5)
    - 1951 (Folder 3: 6)
    - 1952 (Folder 3: 7-8)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
    - 1954 (Folder 4: 3)
    - 1955-1960 (Folder 4: 4)
    - 1963-1965 (Folder 4: 5)
    - 1966 (Folder 4: 6)
    - 1967 (Folder 5: 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 5: 2)
    - 1970-1975 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Printed matter
    - Clippings
      - 1941-1951 (Folder 5: 4)
      - 1952 (Folder 5: 5-7)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
      - 1953-1955 (Folder 6: 3)
      - 1957-1968 (Folder 6: 4)
    - Flyers and bulletins of the Russian Center, 1940 and 1950, and undated (Folder 6: 5)
    - Miscellany (Folder 6: 6)
  - Speeches by unidentified persons, 1953 and undated (Folder 6: 7)
  - Subject file
    - Concert-balls and theatrical performances
      - General
        - 1949-1950 (Folder 6: 8)
        - 1951-1968 (Folder 6: 9)
      - Programs, 1930-1980 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Exhibition of Russian artists in the Russian Center, 1952
      - General (Folder 7: 2)
      - Clippings (Folder 7: 3)
    - Invalid Balls
      - General, 1952-1966 (Folder 7: 4)
      - Programs, 1937-1965 (Folder 7: 5)
    - Marly, Anna (Folder 7: 6)
    - Project of the pin for the Russian Center, 1940 (Folder 7: 7)
    - Natsional'no-Trudovoi Soiuz (NTS), n.d. (Folder 7: 8)
    - Rossiiskii Politicheskii Komitet v N'iu Iorke, 1953-1954 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Russian Club, San Francisco. Liquidation records, 1937 (Folder 7: 10)
    - Russian Home of St. Vladimir, 1956 (Folder 7: 11)
    - Russko-Amerikanskoe Obshchestvo (Russian-American Society), 1951-1953 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Subdivisions of the Russian Center
      - Arbitration Court (Folder 7: 13)
      - Facilities administration
        - General (Folder 7: 14)
        - Minutes of meetings, 1951-1966 (Folder 7: 15)
      - Sports Club (Folder 7: 16)
      - Women's Club (Folder 7: 17)
      - Youth Group (Folder 7: 18)
    - Vserossiiskii komitet osvobozhdeniia, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Zamarev-Veimarn, Mikhail Aleksandrovich (Folder 8: 2)
    - Miscellany (Folder 8: 3)
- RUSSKAIA ZHIZN' FILE, 1942-1989
  See also OVERSIZE FILE/Scrapbooks/ Russkaia zhizn' and PHOTOGRAPHS
  - General (Folder 8: 4)
  - Articles submitted for publication, 1952-1989 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Charter, 1950 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Clippings, 1952-1954 (Folder 8: 7-8)
  - Correspondence.
    - General
      - 1942-1953 (Folder 8: 9)
      - 1954-1979 (Folder 8: 10)
    - American Committee for the Liberation of the People of Russia and United States Information Agency, 1952-1954 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Court records, 1958 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Financial records
    - 1944-1951 (Folder 9: 2)
    - 1952 (Folder 9: 3)
    - 1953 (Folder 9: 4)
    - 1954 (Folder 9: 5)
    - 1955 (Folder 9: 6)
    - 1956 (Folder 9: 7)
    - 1957 (Folder 9: 8)
    - 1958-1962 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Historical sketch about the origins of Russkaia zhizn' (Folder 10: 2)
  - Minutes of meetings.
    - 1949-1952 (Folder 10: 3)
    - 1953-1968 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Poster for the 25 th anniversary of Russkaia zhizn' (Folder 10: 5)
  - Program (Folder 10: 6)
  - Scrapbook.
    See OVERSIZE FILE
  - Miscellany (Folder 10: 7)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1905-1983
  - Baikov, Nikolai Apollonovich. (Folder 10: 8)
    Clippings about him and reviews of his books
  - Boy scouts--Russia. (Box-folder 11: 1-5)
    Includes clippings, correspondence, printed matter and writings relating to the history of scouting in pre-Revolutionary Russia and Russian Boy scout organizations abroad following the Revolution, especially in the United States
  - China--Politics and government, 1912-1949. (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
    Brochures, bulletins and documents on inter-war China, published in Chinese and English in China
  - Chinese Eastern Railway. (Folder 12: 3-4)
    See also Russians--China.
    Correspondence, reports, and other documents relating to the Railway, including a chronology of events prepared for the 25 th anniversary (1922) and summaries of the local and foreign press for 1919
  - Chinese Eastern Railway (Contd.) (Folder 13: 1)
  - Christian sects. (Folder 13: 2)
    Clippings on Russian Baptists, Dukhobors, Molokans, and Old Believers in Canada, Russia, the Soviet Union and the United States
  - General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus. (Folder 13: 3)
    Autographed souvenir program
  - Japan--Foreign relations, 1912-1945. (Folder 13: 4)
    Clippings from Russian émigré newspapers on Japanese-Soviet and Sino-Japanese relations, including the Japanese occupation of Manchuria
  - Kamchatka, Russia. (Folder 13: 5)
    Clippings relating primarily to the history of the Kamchatka Peninsula in the 18 th and 19 th centuries and the founding of Petropavlovsk-na-Kamchatke
  - Lermontov, Mikhail Iur'evich (Folder 13: 6)
  - Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. (Folder 13: 7)
    Includes draft of by-laws, correspondence, reports and other matter pertaining to the Museum's activities
  - Romanov, House of. (Folder 13: 8)
    Clippings, speeches and a report by V. M. Rudnev entitled "Pravda o russkoi tsarskoi sem'e i temnykh silakh" (Ekaterinodar, 1919)
  - Romanov, House of (Contd.) (Folder 14: 1)
  - Russia
    - History
      - 1689-1801 (Folder 14: 2)
      - Nicholas II, 1894-1917. (Folder 14: 3-7)
        Clippings relating to historical figures and events, 1905-1907, 1911-1912, and 1915
    - History, Military-- 1801-1917. (Folder 14: 8)
      See also Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905, and Miscellany/Clippings.
      Clippings and writings relating to military and naval battles, educational establishments, and training, as well as biographical information on various officers. Includes material on the First World War
    - History, Military-- 1801-1917 (Contd.) (Folder 15: 1-2)
  - Russians
    - China. (Folder 15: 3-4)
      See also Chinese Eastern Railway.
      Includes information about the evacuation of Russians from China following the Second World War, and on displaced persons in general
    - China (Contd.) (Folder 16: 1-3)
    - China (Contd.) (Folder 17: 1-2)
    - Foreign countries (Folder 17: 3-5)
    - Germany (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - United States (Folder 18: 2-4)
  - Russkaia Pravoslavnaia Tserkov'--United States. (Folder 18: 5)
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS.
    The bulk of these clippings, other printed matter, and correspondence, relates to conflicts over the construction of the Russian Orthodox Cathedral on Geary Street, San Francisco, California, in the 1960s
  - Russkaia Pravoslavnaia Tserkov'--United States (Contd.) (Folder 19: 1-5)
  - Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 20: 1)
    See also Russia--History, Military--1801-1917
  - San Francisco Committee for the Aid of Russian Disabled Veterans Outside of Russia. (Folder 20: 2)
    Clippings, correspondence, programs and other records relating primarily to the organization of benefit concerts and balls
  - Soviet Union--History
    - Revolution, 1917-1921. (Folder 20: 3-5)
      See also Russia--History, Military--1801-1917, and Miscellany.
      Includes clippings of a biographical nature on various individuals, primarily military leaders, involved in the Civil War (A. V. Kolchak, Iu. K. Stark, S. S. Tolstov, P. V. Vologodskii, and others)
    - 1925-1953 (Box-folder 21: 1-4)
    - 1925-1953 (Box-folder 22: 1-2)
    - 1953-1985 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Soviet Union--History, Military. (Folder 22: 4)
    Relates primarily to the Red Army and Navy in the inter-war period, with a significant volume on the Red Army in the Russian Far East
  - Trotsky, Leon. (Folder 22: 5)
    Clippings relating to his death
  - Ungern von Shternberg, Roman (Folder 22: 6)
  - Miscellany (Box 23)
    - Clippings of a biographical nature (predominantly obituaries) on various prominent Russians (mainly military men) active in the first half of the 20 th century. (Folder 23: 1)
      Indexed file includes materials on Adm. A. V. Kolchak, Gen. A. P. Kutepov, Gen. N. N. Iudenich, Gen. A. A. Vlasov, Prince Felix Iusupov, Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich, and others
    - Miscellany, excluding clippings: (Folder 23: 2)
      see PRINTED MATTER/Clippings, which consists of clippings from various sources not organized by subject
- PRINTED MATTER, 1901-1978
  - Booklets and journals
    - General (Folder 23: 3)
    - Chuzhbina, Brisbane (Australia), #4, (March 1930) (Folder 23: 4)
    - The Constitutionalist: Published monthly at Shanghai, China by the Constitutional Defence League, Shanghai, Vol.1, #8, #9, (December 1926) (January 1927) (Folder 23: 5)
    - Dal'nevostochnyi Institut Eksperimental'noi Meditsiny. Kratkoe obozrienie ispytannykh lechebnykh preparatov, v tom chislie i novieishikh, nashedshikh u Instituta osobennoe odobrenie i rekomenduemykh imi, Harbin (Folder 23: 6)
    - Dal'nevostochnyi vrachebnyi viestnik: Organ Obshchestva russkikh vrachei v Shanhaie, Shanghai, #6, (June 1933) (Folder 23: 7)
    - Dlia Vas, Brisbane (Australia), #2-8, (1977-1978) (Folder 23: 8)
    - Drug politsii, Harbin, #8, (1 August 1939) (Folder 23: 9)
    - Golos Rossii: Organ Dal'ne-vostochnago otdiela russkago obshche-voinskago soiuza/organ anti-sovietskago emigranta, Shanghai, #8, #13-14, #15-16, (1 March 1932) (September-October 1932) (November-December 1932) (Folder 23: 10)
    - Iuridicheskii fakul'tet O. R. S. M., Harbin, 1935 (Folder 23: 11)
    - Iuvenalii, Archimandrite, Narechenie i Khirotoniia o. Arkhimandrita Iuvenaliia vo Episkopa Sin'tszianskago, Harbin, 1935 (Folder 23: 12)
    - Izsleiedovaniia khimicheskago sostava i perevarimosti kitaiskikh kormovykh veshchestv(solomy zemlianogo orekha, v'iushchikhsia steblei sladkogo kartofelia i list'ev gaoliana), Shanghai, 1920 (Folder 23: 13)
    - Izvestiia Vostochnago Instituta, Vladivostok, Volume II, Volume X, (1901) (1904) (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
    - Khlieb nebesnyi, Harbin, #7, #3, #10, #11, #6, #9-10, (November 1936) (March 1937) (October 1939) (November 1940) (June 1943) (September-October 1944) (Folder 24: 3)
    - Krasnyi Krest: Sbornik Mariinskoi obshchiny sester miloserdiia Rossiiskago Obshchestva Krasnago Kresta, Harbin, August 1936 (Folder 24: 4)
    - Luch Azii, Harbin, #35/7, (July 1937) (Folder 24: 5)
    - Matsokin, N. P., Shan'dunskie byki i produkty zhivotnovodstva v Shan'dunie, Shanghai, 1920 (Folder 24: 6)
    - Meshcherskii, A. S., Avtonomnaia Barga, Shanghai, 1920 (Folder 24: 7)
    - Mushketer, Harbin,,, #4, #5,,, #11, #12, #12-b, April-May 1929 September-November 1929 (April 1930) (May-July 1930) October-December n.d. (1934?) (October 1935) (November 1935) 26 August 1936? (Folder 24: 8)
      Includes offprint from magazine Sie-Khe-Khoi entitled Mushketery, August 1937?
    - Novaia Niva n.p., #6, (5 February 1927) (Folder 24: 9)
    - Paskhal'nyi perezvon, Shanghai, April-May 1935 (Folder 24: 10)
    - Put' Khristov, Harbin, #1, #4, (January 1925) (January 1926) (Folder 24: 11)
    - Rubezh, Harbin, #44-52, #13, (1939) (23 March 1940) (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Rus' Sviatogo Vladimira: Iubileinyi sbornik ko dniu 950-letiia Kreshcheniia Rusi, Shanghai, 1938 (Folder 25: 2)
    - Sbornik tserkovno-obshchestvennoi mysli: Spring-1948 god, London (Folder 25: 3)
    - Solntse Rossii, Petrograd, #209, #273, #278, #279 ,#285, #288, #295, #297, #52(?), #315, #361., (February 1914) (May 1915) (June 1915) (June 1915) (August 1915) (August 1915) (October 1915) (October 1915) (December 1915) (March 1916) (January 1917) (Folder 25: 4)
      Includes incomplete issues
    - Tsarskaia krov': Odnodnevnyi sbornik russkoi mysli, Harbin, July 1935 (Folder 25: 5)
    - Tserkovnyi kolokol, Sydney, #2., (April 1932) (Folder 25: 6)
      Includes one page from magazine Put' Emigranta, #2
    - Vera i zhizn', Harbin, February 1935 (Folder 25: 7)
    - Vestnik Kitaia, Tientsin, #1-4, (1936) (Folder 25: 8)
    - Viestnik Pervoi Pekinskoi Tiur'my, Peking, #1-7., (1923) (Folder 25: 9)
      Includes historical sketch about the origins of the Vestnik Pervoi Pekinskoi Tiur'my
    - Zhiganov, V., V zashchitu Rodiny: Po zavietam imperatorov, Shanghai, 1941 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Charters
    - Ustav Man'chzhurskago pedagogicheskago obshchestva, Harbin, 1911 (Folder 25: 11)
    - Ustav obshchestva "Vozrozhdeniia Rossii", Harbin, 1918 (Folder 25: 12)
  - Clippings.
    See also OVERSIZE FILE/Clippings
    - General. (Folder 25: 13-14)
      The majority of these clippings are from the Far Eastern Russian émigré press
    - General (Contd.) (Folder 26: 1)
    - Arranged alphabetically by author
      - Abdank-Kossovskii, Vl. (Folder 26: 2)
      - Galich, Iu. (Folder 26: 3)
      - Iliina-Voieikova, N. (Folder 26: 4)
      - Lukash, I. (Folder 26: 5)
      - Rennikov, A. (Folder 26: 6)
      - Roshchin, N. (Folder 26: 7)
      - Vol'fgang, Br. (Folder 26: 8)
    - Indexed at the folder level by author and/or title, but otherwise unarranged. (Folder 26: 9-13)
    - Indexed (Contd.) (Folder 27: 1-6)
    - Indexed (Contd.) (Folder 28: 1-7)
    - Indexed (Contd.) (Folder 29: 1-4)
  - Newspaper issues.
    Includes incomplete issues and clippings
    - Aziia, Tsindao, #544, (16 June 1942) (Folder 29: 5)
    - Edinenie, Sydney, #9, (3 March 1978) (Folder 29: 6)
    - Ekonomist: Odnodnevnaia akademicheskaia studencheskaia gazeta, Harbin, #1, (May 1928) (Folder 29: 7)
    - Georgievskii den', n.p., n.d. (Folder 29: 8)
    - Golos emigrantov, n.p.,, two incomplete issues, 1939-1940 (Folder 29: 9)
    - Golos Mushketera, Harbin, January 1938? (Folder 29: 10)
    - Golos Rossii, San Francisco, #1-2, #4, #6, (March 1968) (April 1968) (July 1968) (Folder 29: 11)
    - Kharbinskoe vremia, Harbin, #1., (1 January 1940) (Folder 29: 12)
      Includes three incomplete issues, 1932-1940
    - Kitaisko-russkaia gazeta, Shanghai.
    - Komar,, trial issue of satirical newspaper of the Russian Club in San Francisco, n.d. (Folder 29: 13)
    - Mukden, Mukden, #1, (14 December 1930) (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - Nash put', Shanghai, #42, #71., (8 February 1942) (4 October 1942) (Folder 30: 2)
      Includes one clipping
    - Nashe vremia, San Francisco, #234, #255, (26-27 August 1955) (27-28 January 1956) (Folder 30: 3)